https://www.ockendenprizes.org/privacy-policy/

Home / Privacy Policy
Ockenden International (‘we’ ‘our’ and/or ‘us’ being interpreted accordingly) is committed to protecting your privacy and personal information. This edition of our Privacy Policy has been updated to comply with the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR), which came into force on May 25, 2018.If these changes affect how your Personal Information is processed, Ockenden International will take all practicable steps to inform you.From time to time, Ockenden International may change its Privacy Policy. In that case, the ‘last updated’ date at the bottom of this page will also change. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will apply to you and your Personal Information immediately. Changes to this Privacy PolicyThis Privacy Policy (‘Privacy Policy’) explains how Ockenden International use personal information that enables us to identify you personally, such as your email address, phone number, name, title and home or work address (‘Personal Information’) about you that we may collect through this website https://ockendenprizes.org (‘Site’), personal contact and/or post.What personal information does Ockenden International collect?The Personal Information about you that we collect and use includes the following::Your name, address, phone number and other contact details;Your job role and other information provided at point of entry into the annual Ockenden International Prizes for refugee projects;Details of your communications with us;Records regarding donations you have made; and;Details regarding your use of this site (see ‘Cookies’ section below as well as any other Personal Information that you may provide to us from time to time.How does Ockenden International collect my Personal Information?Ockenden International collects Personal Information when you submit personal details while using this Site. For example, when you make a donation, sign up as a supporter, apply to take part in the Ockenden International Prizes, submit a survey form, or you ask to receive further information about Ockenden International and its activities.We may also receive Personal Information from referees provided, education providers and publically available resources (e.g. LinkedIn your own or associated organisations’ websites and/or business associations and/or public records) to verify the identity and credentials of individuals identified on entry forms.Information about third partiesPlease ensure that any Personal Information you supply to us which relates to third party individuals is provided to us with their knowledge of our proposed use of the Personal Information.How does Ockenden International use personal data that I provide?Any personal data and other information we collect about you through this Site is in accordance with this Privacy Policy and for the following purposes:to enable you to make donations and conduct other transactions through this Site;to help us understand more about how our Site is used and improve the Site and other services that we provide;to be able to send you communications, sometimes using third-party distribution apps such as Mail Chimp, that may be of interest to you, either electronically or otherwise;to publicise our projects and donations made (provided these are not made anonymously);to operate and administer the Ockenden International Prizes and publicise the competition, annual call for entries and competition results including publishing the identities of winners through various media; to judge entries made for the Ockenden International Prizes;to keep records of our activities, entries and winners, including the projects that they work on;to do anything else that you ask us to or which we do with your prior consent;we may also use the data operationally, such as analysis of our performance or enable us to comply with relevant legal or regulatory obligations.We process your Personal Information for the above purposes relying on one or more of the following lawful grounds:The lawful grounds on which we collect and process your Personal Information if you have indicated that you are interested in receiving regular information about Ockenden International’s work or appeals we will send you communications about these, either electronically or otherwise. In addition, we may send you direct mail that we feel may be of interest to you. You are free to opt out of receiving such communications or direct mail at any time by clicking on the Unsubscribe link and/or contacting us at the address provided below.where you have freely provided your specific, informed and unambiguous consent for particular purposes;where we agree to provide services to you, in order to take any pre-contract steps at your request and/or to perform our contractual obligations to you;where we need to use your Personal Information for legitimate purposes relevant to us being able to administrate the organisation and its activities, evaluate and improve our processes and operations, and ensure compliance with applicable law. We will always seek to pursue these legitimate interests in a way that does not unduly infringe on your other legal rights and freedoms and, in particular, your right of privacy;where we need to protect your vital interests or those of someone else (such as in a medical emergency) and/orwhere we need to collect, process or hold your Personal Information to comply with a legal obligation.If we process ‘special category’ or ‘sensitive’ Personal Information (e.g. information regarding your health, religious beliefs or ethnicity) we will only do this with your explicit consent; or, to protect your vital interests (or those of someone else) in an emergency; or, where you have already publicised such information; or, where we need to use such sensitive data in connection with a legal claim that we have or may be subject to.Our legal obligations regarding your Personal InformationWe collect and process your Personal Information in accordance with applicable law. This includes, without limitation, the EU General Data Protection Regulation (2016/679) and the UK Data Protection Act 2018 together with other applicable UK and EU laws that regulate the collection, processing and privacy of your Personal Information (together, ‘Data Protection Law’).Who we share your Personal Information with?Ockenden International does not sell or rent information about its Site users to anyone. When you are on this Site and are asked for your personal data, you are sharing that information with Ockenden International alone unless you are informed otherwise in this Privacy Policy (or elsewhere) or it is clear that you are dealing with a third party when you submit your personal data. For example, where you elect to use our secure online donation pages you would be passed through to the website of our partner company, JustGiving.com where it would be readily apparent that you are using the JustGiving.com website. Please note that when you submit your details to a partner website such as JustGiving.com or another third party website, you will be subject to privacy policies and practices in accordance with the terms of use and privacy notices or policies on that website.You can also request information regarding the personal data which we hold about you in accordance with your rights under applicable data protection law. If you would like to make such a request please contact us at the above address, giving us as much detail as possible about the particular personal information that you seek. Please note that (as permitted by applicable law) before we can provide you with the information you seek, we may have to ask you to verify your identity and charge a small administration fee for dealing with your request.Ockenden International does not have any control over JustGiving.com or other third party websites to which we link and we are not responsible for the privacy of any personal data which you provide after you have used a link on our website to visit a third party site. You should always review the applicable terms of use, privacy policy or statements appearing on such a third party site to make sure that you are happy with them. We may need to disclose your Personal Information to certain third party organisations who are handling that data only on our behalf and in accordance with our instructions under contract in the following circumstances:companies that act as our service providers that have been engaged to perform certain technical or administrative support tasks on our behalf such as data hosting, system maintenance or database management. We will allow those parties access to personal data solely for the purpose of them being able to perform the services assigned to them; andwe may process your data and provide it to other parties for the purposes of conducting fraud checks and crime prevention.We may pass personal data regarding our Site users to the police, courts or regulatory authorities or may be required to pass such information to third parties in order to comply with legal obligations.In all cases we always aim to ensure that your Personal Information is only used by third parties for lawful purposes and in compliance applicable Data Protection Law.How long do we keep your data?We only hold your personal data for as long as it is needed for the purposes set out in this document.Children’s privacy protectionOckenden International’s target audience is not intentionally aimed at children 13 years of age or younger. We do not intentionally collect or maintain data about anyone under the age of 13.How does Ockenden International protect my personal data?Ockenden International is committed to taking reasonable steps to protect the personal data that you provide to us. We take appropriate technical and organisational security measures to protect your personal data against unauthorised or unlawful processing, and accidental loss, destruction or damage.Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal data as set out in this Privacy Policy, Ockenden International cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us by email and other forms of communication over a public network. Such transmission is at your own risk.Where will Ockenden International locate my Personal Information?If you provide Personal Information to Ockenden International, this will primarily be processed in the United Kingdom and other parts of the European Economic Area (“EEA”). However, in some cases your Personal Information may be transmitted or made available to selected staff or authorised contractors providing services to Ockenden International who are located in the United States and/or another non-EEA country. The law in the United States and those other non-EEA countries may not provide the same legal standards for protection of Personal Information that you are entitled to in the EEA.In order to safeguard your Personal Information, we only conduct such transfers under a contract or another appropriate mechanism which is authorised under Data Protection Law. This is to make sure that your Personal Information is safeguarded in accordance with the same legal standards that apply to us in the United Kingdom.Our Site uses CookiesLike many websites, this Site also uses “cookies” in order to provide you with a more personalised web service.The cookie that we use on this Site is a text-only string of information that we pass to your computer’s or electronic device’s hard drive through your web-browser so that this Site can remember who you are. Cookies cannot be used by themselves to identify you. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the ‘lifetime’ of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number.For more information about cookies, please see www.allaboutcookies.org.If you do not wish to receive cookies you can easily modify your web browser to refuse cookies, or to notify you when you receive a new cookie. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features of our Site if cookies are disabled, and so in order to enjoy the Site to the full, we recommend that you leave them switched on.For instructions on how to stop cookies being installed on your browser, please see www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies.What is Ockenden lnternational’s policy on allowing me to update, correct, delete or review my Personal Information?You can also request information regarding the Personal Information which we hold about you in accordance with your rights under applicable data protection law. If you would like to make such a request please contact our Data Protection Lead at enquiries@ockendenprizes.org and/or the above address, giving us as much detail as possible about the particular Personal Information that you seek. Please note that (as permitted by applicable law) before we can provide you with the information you seek, we may have to ask you to verify your identity and charge a small administration fee for dealing with your request.Under Data Protection Law you also have the following rights, which are exercisable by making a request to us in writing:that we correct Personal Information that we hold about you which is inaccurate or incomplete;that we erase your Personal Information without undue delay if we no longer need to hold or process it;to object to any automated processing (if applicable) that we carry out in relation to your Personal Information, for example if we conduct any automated credit scoring;to object to our use of your Personal Information for direct marketing; to object and/or to restrict the use of your Personal Information for purpose other than those set out above unless we have a legitimate reason for continuing to use it; orthat we transfer Personal Information to another party where the Personal Information has been collected with your consent or is being used to perform contact with you and is being carries out by automated means.If you would like to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us using the contact details provided in this Privacy Policy.All of these requests may be forwarded on to a third party provider who is involved in the processing of your Personal Information on our behalf.If you make a request and are not satisfied with our response, or believe that we are illegally processing your Personal Information, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) – see https://ico.org.uk/.If, for example, you change your email address or become aware that any of the other information we hold about you is inaccurate or out of date or if you wish to opt-out of receiving any further direct mailings from us, you can simply email us at enquiries@ockendenprizes.org and/or write to our:Contact usIf have any questions about anything in this document or think that your personal data has been misused or mishandled, our Data Protection Lead can be reached at enquiries@ockendenprizes.org or by post at:Data Protection LeadOckenden Internationalc/- Context Graphics Limited1 Savernake Court,Old Church LaneStanmoreMiddlesex HA7 2RJUnited KingdomDate published: 1st September 2018
PO Box 516,
Twickenham,
TW1 9PD
enquiries@ockendenprizes.org
About Us For more than 65 years, Ockenden International has helped refugees and displaced people across the globe.
Read more . . .
More InformationGoals & Purposes
Affiliates
History
Timeline
Trustees
Joyce Pearce Junior Research Fellow
Donations
Prizes and Winners2020 Prize Winners
2013 Winner
Ockenden International is a registered charity in England and Wales (1053720). A company limited by guarantee registered in England and Wales (3171090). Registered address: 20 Old Bailey, London EC4M 7AN
© Copyright 2019 Ockenden International. All Rights Reserved. Website by DogFish Design
and Context Graphics Limited.
Links
Disclaimer
Privacy Policy
Ockenden International uses cookies to improve the site user experience.
The assumption is that you're ok with this, but you can opt-out if you wish.AcceptReject Read MorePrivacy & Cookies Policy
To learn more about make donate charity with us visit our "Contact us" site. By calling +44(0) 800 883 8450 .
